Well Chris, we've learned a lot about networking so far.
Chris 到目前为止 我们已经了解了 网络方面的许多知识
So how are you feeling about getting some of that sweet,
那么你觉得把这些 可爱的网络代码
sweet networking code baked into our Quake Report app?
加入我们的 Quake Report 应用怎么样?
&gt;&gt; I'm pretty pumped.
我也很希望这样
We've made some good progress so far.
目前我们已经取得了一些不错的进展
I'd really like to get this app talking to the USGS.
我真的很想将款 应用与 USGS 对接
So we can get some live data into the app.
这样就可以为这个应用 输入一些实时数据
&gt;&gt; Indeed, there's just a couple more concepts that we need to understand.
的确如此 但我们还需要了解 一些概念
&gt;&gt; Wait, which ones?
等一下 哪些概念?
&gt;&gt; Well, when handling network calls,
你知道的 处理网络调用时
we're relying on a lot of things to happen in a timely manner as you know.
我们需要许多 操作及时发生
The device needs to connect to the wireless signal and
设备需要与无线信号 连接并
send a request, then the server has to create a response and send it back.
发送请求 然后服务器必须创建 响应并将其送回
This can take an unknown amount of time, and we want the app to perform
这不知道要花费多少时间 而我们希望应用能够同时
other tasks in the meantime, such as responding to user input.
执行其他任务 例如 响应用户输入
Working on several different tasks at the same time is known as multitasking.
同时处理多个不同的任务 被称为多任务处理
&gt;&gt; [LAUGH] Yeah, I'm great a multitasking.
是的 我很擅长多任务处理
&gt;&gt; [LAUGH] Yeah.
没错
You can think of tasks as threads in Java.
你可以将任务看做 Java 中的线程
In this lesson, we'll show you how our app can take advantage of more than
这节课 我们将为你介绍我们的 应用如何同时利用
one thread at the same time.
多个线程
Now a single thread executes one task at a time in order,
现在 一个线程按顺序 一次执行一个任务
even when one of the tasks takes longer than expected.
即使其中一项任务花费的时间比 预期长 亦是如此
For example, imagine that you're baking something, and
例如 假设你正在 烘烤一些东西
the first step is to preheat the oven.
第一步要做的就是预热烤箱
&gt;&gt; Okay.
嗯
&gt;&gt; Well, what if you had to wait for
那么 如果你必须等到
your oven to warm to 400 degrees before you could do anything else?
烤箱预热至 400 度才能 做别的事情 怎么办?
That'd be a bunch of wasted time, right?
那要浪费很多的时间 对吧?
&gt;&gt; Yeah, for sure.
是的
&gt;&gt; Now it'd be much better if you could chop up the veggies and
现在 如果可以在预热 烤箱的同时切好蔬菜
season the meat at the same time that the oven was heating up.
并腌制肉类 就好了
Computers follow the same philosophy of trying to get
计算机也遵循同样的 理念 一直尝试能够
things done at the same time, and we call this multitasking.
同时执行任务 我们称之为多任务处理
At any rate, threads and parallelism are fundamental concepts of
无论如何 线程和 并行都是计算机科学的
computer science, and you'll get a taste of them in this lesson.
基本概念 在本节课 你将 亲自了解这些概念
I thought it would be great to introduce a small sample app for
我觉得最好是先介绍一个 简单的示例应用
the student to become comfortable with these ideas first.
以便学生了解这些 概念
&gt;&gt; Wait, hold on a second.
等一下
Another simple app?
其他示例应用?
&gt;&gt; Yeah, trust me.
是的 相信我
It's a very small one called the Did You Feel It app.
这是一个非常简单的应用 叫做 Did You Feel It 应用
Once they get comfortable with these concepts of threads, I'll send them off
等学生们了解了这些线程的 概念之后 我会把他们送到
to you so you can help them update the Quake Report app, deal?
你那去 这样你就可以帮助他们更新 Quake Report 应用 可以吗?
&gt;&gt; [SOUND] Okay, deal.
好的 就这么定了
At that point you'll be able to modify the Quake Report app to go fetch some
到那时 你将可以修改 Quake Report 应用以便
earthquake data from the server, and at the same time,
从服务器中提取地震数据  同时
be ready to respond to user input.
可以响应用户输入
&gt;&gt; These concepts can be a challenge, even for advanced developers.
即便是高级的开发人员 理解这些概念也有一定的难度
So don't worry if you don't understand them right away.
所以 如果你不能立刻理解 请不要着急
&gt;&gt; Agreed, and one more thing.
没错 另外
Another fundamental idea in building apps is handling errors properly.
构建应用中的另一个基本理念是 正确处理错误
That is, planning ahead for unique conditions in which your app may not be
也就是 对于应用可能 无法按预期执行功能的
able to perform the functions as expected.
特殊情况提前 进行计划
So it's always a good idea to consider these what if scenarios, and
所以考虑这些假设情景 然后对代码做出必要的调整以便
then make the necessary adjustments in code to handle them gracefully.
做出得体的处理 一直是个好主意
&gt;&gt; Cool, so in lesson three, we're going to learn about threads and
厉害 所以在第三节课 我们将会学习线程和
parallelism, and finally update the Quake Report with
并行 并最终 使用端到端网络代码
the end to end networking code to fetch the data from the server.
更新 Quake Report 以便 从服务器提取数据
&gt;&gt; Sounds good.
听起来不错